[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 27]
Chunzhi.
Your bow.
I've wrapped it for you.
Since I married you,
in this life,
I will always be by your side.
The Marquis has just died,
yet as his soldiers,
how dare you massacre the people?
You also came from the people.
You also have family and parents.
Is your courage
all used to slaughter your own kin?
Fellow villagers!
Fight them!
Kill!
Charge!
Stop!
Stop it, all of you!
I, Shen Run,
am here with the Marquis of Danyang.
Who dares to be insolent?
You-
Eunuch Xia.
I heard you served the late Emperor for decades
without making a single mistake.
How is it that when serving me,
you can't even hold a bowl of ginseng soup properly?
This old servant
deserves to die!
I have done my best
to serve Your Majesty for years.
From now on,
I will obey your edicts
and never act without your permission.
Please forgive me, Your Majesty.
You saw the situation in the court today.
Hundreds of officials have impeached you.
Look at the bunch of people you've taken under your wing
and the mess they've made of Hengtang.
Peasant uprisings
have been a sign of a nation’s downfall since ancient times.
If I forgive you,
will the people forgive me?
You better
drink this bowl of soup, Eunuch Xia.
Eunuch Xia.
Commander Shen.
You made such a huge scene
capturing a mere County Sheriff.
But here I am, the dignified Commissioner Hu,
and you chose
to come along?
You're hurting my pride.
Outside, the public is furious.
In court, the officials are impeaching you.
Isn't this scene
big enough?
Commissioner Hu,
even at this point,
you are still so greedy.
I admit defeat.
I lost to you.
Come.
Escort me to the capital now.
No need to return to the capital.
Commissioner Hu.
You've been drinking
this aged wine since the time of the late emperor.
It's time to change your taste.
Try this wine bestowed upon you by the Emperor.
Brilliant move, Commander.
Impressive.
Since the late emperor's time,
you have relied on Eunuch Xia as your backer,
leaving chronic problems in Hengtang.
First, officials at all levels
invented various excuses
to increase taxes and corvée,
overwhelming the common people
and causing them to lose their land.
The noble families took the opportunity to annex land,
expanding their estates.
Once they grew strong,
they began to conceal their land
and pay fewer taxes.
With officials protecting each other,
Hengtang
had long been impenetrable.
My father proposed the Equalization Law
to remeasure land nationwide
and levy taxes by the mu.
Those with more land would pay more,
those with less would pay less,
and those with none would pay nothing.
Taking money from noble families to relieve disaster victims
and equalizing the burden of taxes and corvée
would greatly narrow the absurd gap
between the rich and poor in Hengtang.
Yes.
This is indeed a disruptive policy.
But what it disrupts
is the lives of you corrupt officials and noble families.
But have you ever thought about it?
If taxes and corvée are equalized,
from how many noble families' pockets
will the money be taken?
No matter how much,
they still have to pay.
My father was benevolent.
Though he had a good plan,
he didn't get to enforce it on any noble family.
Then I'll make
the first strike,
starting right here with you, Commissioner Hu.
The late Emperor lacked the resolve to do this.
Will the current Emperor
really do it?
Let me remind you,
we should not
both become bait.
Commissioner Hu.
Once you fall,
the new emperor will see the court's
determination to implement the new policy
and hear the cries of the people.
As long as I accomplish the first strike,
there will naturally be a second
and a third.
Even if the new emperor intends to,
extending it from the capital to Hengtang
will meet with great resistance.
Your father failed to do this.
Do you really think you can?
Commissioner Hu, you love drinking so much.
Have you ever had the wine from the Northern Frontier?
In the Northern Frontier,
I only drank two kinds of wine.
One was on cold nights,
to numb the pain
when it was unbearable.
The other
was to see my brothers off when they die
before my eyes in battle.
I often wonder,
when we defend our nations with our lives,
whose homes are we defending?
The homes of you corrupt officials and noble families
who feed on the people?
Foreign enemies are hard to fend off.
But you parasites
must also be eliminated.
Although my father is dead,
there are fortunately countless people like him in this world,
helping me in secret
and paving my way to the new Emperor's side.
My father's ideal...
Our ideal,
is now
almost achieved.
Speaking of which,
I must thank your good brother-in-law.
If it weren't for his help,
it wouldn't have progressed so quickly.
He handed over all the evidence of the crimes committed
by you and Eunuch Xia.
My brother-in-law,
Xie Shu,
cut off his tail to survive.
You instigated him to frame my father back then.
Now, he's repeating his old trick
to bring down your Zuixian Tavern.
It is the ending you deserve.
Your father
was indeed innocent.
He was truly incorruptible.
I spent over a month
fabricating many of his crimes,
but the late Emperor didn't believe them.
It was Xie Shu
who personally forged the false evidence
that your father, as the Jiangnan Transport Commissioner,
profited from canal transport.
This finally angered the late Emperor,
causing the extermination of the Shen family.
After your Zuixian Tavern falls,
the next
will be the Xie Residence.
I just want to
remind you of something.
Do you really think Xie Shu
turned against your father
just to get a promotion?
Couldn't it be
that your father
knew some
huge secret about Xie Shu?
You mean,
there's another story behind this?
When I was investigating your father,
I accidentally learned that
at the last moment before he went to the Censorate for interrogation,
he told this matter
to your wife's birth mother,
Jin Chunqing.
Shen.
It's already nice that you're visiting.
Why did you bring so many gifts?
You are too kind.
I was just passing by,
so I brought you some New Year goods.
That day, my father
took me to Yunya's house.
So it was to...
Well,
I've said what I should.
What an exquisite wine cup.
It's a pity
it's containing this.
Commissioner Hu.
Your defeat is sealed.
Looking back on this journey,
have you ever regretted it?
A defeat is a defeat.
What is there to regret?
Qingyuan.
It's rare for you to visit.
Today,
I will show off my skills so you can
have a taste of my cooking.
Have a seat.
I'll be done in a minute.
Coming.
Smells so good.
Are you planning to open a restaurant, Second Young Master?
Oh, stop calling me that.
Maybe not a restaurant,
but I might open a tavern someday.
But I really didn't expect this.
I'm living a good life now.
Every day, I tend to the farm,
feed the chickens,
have simple meals,
and live a carefree life.
As for matters of the Xie family,
I don't know,
and don't care.
I'm not cut out for it anyway.
Baoxian,
come visit often.
Zhengjun,
I'm hungry.
When will it be ready?
Mother, it's almost done.
It's ready.
Coming.
Come on.
Here.
Come.
Let's eat.
Here.
Here, Qingyuan.
Qingyuan.
I'm so happy
that you could come today.
Mother.
Mother,
let's eat.
Eat.
Is Zhenglun still studying?
Zheng...
Call him over.
Zhenglun!
Brother.
-Zhenglun, come and eat. -Come out and eat.
Look at you, you're always so slow.
Mother was calling you.
Hurry.
-Sit down. -Sit down.
Sit down.
Lun.
-Studying is hard work. -Let’s eat.
Don't exhaust yourself.
Come.
Eat.
Mother.
Here.
I stir-fried cabbage for you again. Try it.
Come, try this too.
Come, try it.
This is also delicious.
How is it?
Second Madam,
I came today to ask you
if there's someone
named Lu Lingshu in the Xie Residence.
Mother.
Mother?
It's delicious.
Is it?
Mother,
do you know
who Lu Lingshu is?
Lu Lingshu.
Aren't you Lu Lingshu?
Tell me.
Your Lordship!
I am not from the Xia's faction.
Hu Xing forced me to do everything.
Please believe me, Your Lordship!
Spare me!
I'm innocent!
Coward.
Congratulations, Commander.
After 10 years of hiding,
you finally avenged your father.
What a great trick to escape and deceive everyone.
For this round,
I admit my defeat.
Do you know what it's like to love someone,
Shen Run?
It is wanting to make love with him,
and share the beauty of this world with him.
It's wanting to be with him,
wearing flowers in spring,
boating on summer nights,
climbing high in autumn,
and warming wine by the stove in winter.
You're two blocks of wood with only revenge in your hearts;
what's left in your hearts besides hatred?
I have already heard.
Hu Xing's remaining followers have all been sentenced to death.
Did you come here this time
to see me off one last time?
[Memorial]
My dear Yuting
loves this kind of exquisite vessel the most.
What an exquisite wine cup.
What a pity.
I will never have the chance
to gift her some
fun,
exquisite things again.
Fortunately,
I've wiped away all the matters
she handled.
[The funds amassed over the years were my sole doing; no others were involved.]
[Pei Yuting, Princess of Yongjia, is usually upright and prudent.]
[Her actions resulted from my threat, not from her own volition.]
I will take on
all the blame.
She is still young.
She still has plenty of time.
He said all of his actions
had nothing to do with you.
So His Majesty
ordered me to escort you back to the capital.
This old man...
Mother, you haven't been out lately.
Are you feeling any better?
I feel better.
I called you here today
because I have something to tell you.
Please go ahead, Mother.
I have agreed with your father
that on a sunny day,
we will send you to the capital to visit your relatives.
Visit my relatives?
Your birth mother
still has some relatives
in the capital.
The Xia family
can still more or less
take good care of you.
You are still sick, Mother.
How can I leave?
It's exactly because I'm sick
that we can't delay this any longer.
I must make plans for you ahead of time.
Qingru is already married.
The only one I'm worried about
is you.
Back then,
I even wanted to marry you into the Pei residence.
Who would have thought
that Qinghe would beat you to it?
I even hated the third branch for quite a while.
Mother,
Pei Guanling and Eldest Sister
were mutually in love.
Mother, you should be...
happy for me
that I didn't marry him.
About that Mr. Zhou you like...
I...
actually asked around about him.
He was devoted to you,
studied hard,
and was a good match.
Qingrong.
Don't be sad.
In your life,
you won't just meet Mr. Zhou.
When you get to the capital,
You will meet so many people.
But you must remember this.
Background is not important.
Neither is family status.
None of that matters.
You must find someone
who leaves you with no regrets in this life.
You are smart
and clear-headed.
You've always known what you want.
You definitely won't be like me.
You will live a good life.
Mother...
Remember.
When you get to the capital,
you are just Xia Yingying's daughter.
You have nothing to do
with the Xie family
or me.
From now on,
you must live anew.
You must absolutely
not return to Hengtang.
And there is no need
to worry about me.
Mother.
Mother, you are still gravely ill.
How could I possibly
abandon you?
For so many years,
you raised me.
In my heart,
you are my real mother.
I know...
It's fine.
I will be better after taking the medicine.
It's okay.
Don't be afraid.
It's just a spill.
You can brew another one for me.
I want to drink the medicine you brew.
Hurry,
go.
Go.
Go...
Your father
loved your birth mother so much back then.
Even if she committed a grave crime,
he would never
have had the heart to lay a finger on her.
So why
did he agree to let your birth mother
ask to leave the residence,
then not look for her for 9 years,
only to kill her as soon as he found her?
Everything that happened to your birth mother,
including her death,
is due to Xie Shu's
unspeakable secret.
Madam.
Fourth Lady wants to see you.
I stopped her.
It's time to put an end to this.
Tell her to wait for me in the main hall.
I will go see her.
Yes.
Long time no see.
I'm here.
What do you want?
Can you tell me now
who Lu Lingshu is?
You are indeed smart and capable.
You have discovered
the secret of the bronze mirror.
But what does Lu Lingshu
have to do with you avenging
your mother?
Didn't you want to kill Xie Shu?
Why didn't you kill him?
My brother is dead.
The Hu family is gone.
But Xie Shu is still alive.
What does knowing who Lu Lingshu is
have to do with killing him?
Xie Shu?
Of course I can kill him.
But I want to figure out
why my birth mother died.
Is there anything in this world that can be figured out
and explained clearly?
I’ve lived my whole life,
yet I haven't figured out
what love is.
I thought that
since I married Xie Shu,
as long as I treated him wholeheartedly
and loved him,
he would definitely fall in love with me.
But I've only seen Xie Shu look at your mother
the way Shen Run looks at you.
In his eyes,
I am nothing.
Xia Yingying,
Mei Yinghua, and I.
in Xie Shu's eyes,
we were merely power,
beauty,
and money.
We were just
stepping stones for Xie Shu to climb up.
But your birth mother was different.
She was nothing.
Yet Xie Shu loved her.
He loved her with all his heart.
I hated her.
We all hated her.
We hated her to death.
So,
forcing your birth mother out of the Xie Residence that day
was an unspoken decision shared among us.
You are still too young.
You don't understand what love is.
The word "love"
is sought after by everyone.
But when survival is concerned,
it is abandoned by everyone.
Mother.
You're truly a noble of the Hu family.
Even this sick,
you are still so elegant and graceful.
Nine years ago,
you came to my house wearing that accessory.
At that time, I just thought
that this hairpin
looked stunning
under the sun.
I also thought
the woman wearing this hairpin
was elegant
and extraordinary.
That day,
what exactly did you say to my birth mother?
What does Lu Lingshu
have to do with my birth mother's death?
What exactly is that massive secret?
I've been your mother for a while now.
I should tell you something useful.
Xie Shu...
Is just an imposter.
Everything in the Xie Residence is fake!
You actually want to see me.
Then speak.
What is the matter?
The day before yesterday,
before Shen Zhibai was summoned by the Censorate,
he came to see me.
At that time,
he looked conflicted.
I asked him what had happened,
but he hesitated to speak.
Right before he left,
he finally told me.
Chunqing.
I've kept something from you for over 10 years.
I don't know if I helped you back then
or harmed you.
More than10 years ago,
it was Xie Shu
who personally killed
his father.
I couldn't figure it out back then.
Xie Shu was just born days before
Old Master Xie's death.
How could he have killed his father?
Then I realized
the only possibility.
You actually guessed it.
You knew Xie Shu killed your birth mother.
Why didn't you kill him?
Are you scared?
Are you scared because you've never killed anyone?
Are you afraid of the feeling
of a life slipping through your fingers?
[Qinyue Corridor]
Fifth Concubine, what brings you here?
You lowly performer,
do you really think you're fit to live in Danyue Pavilion?
The courtyard was arranged by the Old Madam.
-If you have any complaints, -Chunqing.
you can...
Shut up!
What are you doing?
Concubine Xia!
Let me tell you,
I'll give you 3 days to move out.
That day,
I finally found a chance
to not only eliminate two threats,
but also use this secret
to threaten Xie Shu.
I know you hate Xia Yingying to the core, My Lord.
But you can't make a move because of her great-uncle.
It doesn't matter.
I...
am willing to be of help.
Fifth Madam,
Fourth Madam told me to bring you this pregnancy tonic.
She also said she would
-move out of Danyue Pavilion soon. -Leave it there.
Let go!
Let go of me!
-Why did you hurt me? -It’s not me!
Let go!
I'll kill you!
It wasn't me.
It wasn't me!
Qingrong.
That day,
I was going to strangle her.
But I just couldn't do it.
Somebody, help!
Someone is dead!
Qingrong.
Shall we have some tangyuan soup together?
Good girl, let's go.
Thank goodness, I didn't do it.
That's how Qingrong became my daughter.
I burned Soul-Suppressing Mantras every day
just to suppress Xia Yingying's soul.
I didn't want her to come back.
I didn't want her to come back
and tell my daughter
what I did to her mother
and the harm I caused her!
So you not only killed my mother,
but also almost killed me too!